

# **Amit Dahat**

DevOps Engineer | Nagpur

# **Summary**

IT Engineer with 6 years of Over all experience, and relevant 4.5 years of specializing DevOps, AWS and Linux . Successfully implemented CI/CD pipelines and virtualization strategies resulting in a reduction of deployment times by 50%. Committed to continuously improving processes and delivering high-quality productsand

# **Experience**

### **DevOps Engineer**

LoginRadius - Oct 2020 - Feb 2024 . 3 Yrs 4 Mos.

100 employees | More Details

Responsibilities

Experience in creating Devops strategy in a mix environment of Linux (WINDOWS, LINUX and UNIX) Instances along with Amazon Web Services. ? Streamlined the CI /CD pipeline for Java-based applications using Maven, resulting in a 20% reduction in build and deployment times. ? Involved heavily in setting up the CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins, Maven, jfrog, GitHub, Ansible and Docker. ? Experienced with Docker container service. Dockerized applications by creating Docker images from Dockerfile and Dockerhub. ? Hands on working experience on Web Server (Apache, Nginx), Application Servers tomcat). ? Introduced version control best practices with Git, improving code collaboration and traceability. ? Provisioning AWS cloud infrastructure using Terraform and configuring them using Ansible. ? Experienced working in AWS cloud computing platform including EC2, S3, AMI, VPC, IAM, Route 53, Cloud watch. ? Experience setting multi region and multi cloud terraform projects

Yash Technologies - Mar 2020 - Jul 2020 . 4 Mos.

8040 employees | Self Funded/Govt/Others | More Details

Software Supply Chain Management Wholesale

Responsibilities

Supported project teams in a Continuous Integration and Continuous deployments environment with Jenkins. Perform Maintenance and troubleshoot the CI/CD systems. ? Setup and configure Devops environment on AWS. ? Manage and configure Continuous deployments on production server like Tomcat by using pipeline ? Implemented continuous delivery pipeline involving Jenkins, Ansible to complete the automation from commit to deployment. ? Knowledge of Configuration management tool, Ansible to deploy critical applications, automates repetitive tasks and proactively manages changes. ? Implemented cost-saving measures, optimizing cloud resource usage and reducing monthly expenses by 25%. ? Monitor AWS resources, set a notification alarm in case of trouble through Cloud Watch. ? Experience in writing Bash Shell.

#### **Linux Engineer**

Trueweb Technologies - Mar 2018 - Mar 2020 . 2 Yrs 0 Mos.

Responsibilities

Worked on Linux platforms Red Hat Linux, Ubuntu which includes installation, configuring and maintenance of applications on this environment. ? Install and configure Jenkins, Ansible, Maven, Git, Docker on linux servers. ? Installed packages using YUM and Red Hat Package Manager (RPM) on various servers. ? Automated routine tasks using shell scripts and Ansible, reducing manual intervention and increasing operational efficiency. ? Monitor AWS resources, set a notification alarm in case of trouble through Cloud Watch. ? Create virtual machines on AWs using EC2 service. Created and manage persistent volumes on to EC2 instances. ? Configure and manage AWS services, (EC2, S3, VPC, Subnets, Internet Gateway,EBS) ? Worked on Identity Access Management IAM like AWS permissions, Roles, Policies, MFA authentication, User permissions and Groups.

#### Education

## Bachelor Of Technology (B.Tech/B.E), Information Technology

2014 - Nagpur University

#### Awards & Certifications

**AWS Developer Associate** 

Amazon Web Services

**Cloud Solution Architect** 

Nasscom